brandman.edu 2019-07-17

# Privacy Policy

Brandman University, a member of the Chapman University System, is committed to protecting your privacy. This Statement of Privacy applies to the Brandman University website and governs data collection and usage. By using the Brandman University website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

**Collection of Your Personal Information**  
Brandman University collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home and/or work address and/or telephone number. Brandman University also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

Our Partners may use cookies, web beacons, and/or other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous statistics about our website visitors. Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“NPII”) data is collected by our Partners, and is used by our Partners for the purpose of online Retargeting reporting web traffic, statistics, advertisement ‘click-throughs,’ and/or other activities on our website. NPII data collected by our Partners for advertising purposes is completely anonymous, and only includes information such as the Prospect’s IP address, date and time of visit, domain type, and their activity on our Advertisers’ and Partners’ websites. None of this information, individually or grouped together, can be traced back to a specific individual.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through Brandman University public message boards, social media sites or forums, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: Brandman University does not read your private online communications with others.

Brandman University encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from Brandman University so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. Brandman University is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites other than those managed by Brandman University or the use of your information by such outside websites.

**Use of Your Personal Information**  
Brandman University collects and uses your personal information to deliver services related to higher education. Brandman University may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you about programs, classes, scholarships, events and other activities related to Brandman University.  Brandman University may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services and programs or of potential new services and programs.

Brandman University does not sell, share, rent or lease its lists to third parties. Brandman University may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis or send you email or postal mail. Such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Brandman University, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Brandman University does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.  Brandman University students’ and applicants’ rights with respect to their education are explicitly protected under the The Federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA).

Brandman University may keep track of the websites and pages you visit within Brandman University, in order to determine what Brandman University services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and marketing within Brandman University to students and prospective students whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

Brandman University websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Brandman University; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Brandman University (including enforcing this agreement); and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Brandman University, or the public.

**Personalizing Your Online Experience**  
The Brandman University website may use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies are not used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Brandman University pages, or register with Brandman University site or services, a cookie helps Brandman University to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information. When you return to the same Brandman University website page, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Brandman University services or websites you visit.

**Rights Regarding Your Information**  
If you provide Brandman University with personal information you thereby give your express consent for Brandman University to contact you by phone, email, mail and/or text message. You have the following rights with respect to that information:

  * To review the user information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that we correct any errors, outdated information, or omissions in user information that you have supplied to us
  * To request that your user information not be used to contact you
  * To request that your user information be removed from any solicitation list that we use
  * To request that your user information be deleted from our records and
  * To opt out of being solicited by this website or third parties

If you request that your user information be deleted from our records, there may be a brief delay in our processing that request, while we verify that the request is valid and originates from you as opposed to an unauthorized third party. If you request that your information be deleted, we reserve the right to terminate and/or limit your access to the Brandman University website.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact [help@brandman.edu](mailto:help@brandman.edu).

**Security of Your Personal Information**  
No method of safeguarding information is 100% secure. Brandman University uses a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Brandman University secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

**Consent**  
By using this site, you signify your consent to Brandman University's online privacy policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use this site. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to update, change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy from time to time.

This Privacy Policy has been developed with the recognition that Internet technologies are rapidly evolving and that underlying standard business models are still not well established. Accordingly, this Privacy & Security Statement is subject to change. Any such changes will be posted on this page and the date will be updated below.

**Last Updated: April 19, 2013**
